<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Folder><_lessonEntry><_entryId><![CDATA[0A878CD39A174261BC2C9EEB962604C5]]></_entryId><_objectId><![CDATA[58C923421A54482BB9B307A3E0E62329]]></_objectId><_parentId><![CDATA[ROOT]]></_parentId><_courseId><![CDATA[MRG-141218-143311-MSS32]]></_courseId><_editableBy>32</_editableBy><_viewableBy>2</_viewableBy><_tracking>1</_tracking><_hidden>0</_hidden><_password /><_userGroup><![CDATA[ALL]]></_userGroup><_startDate /><_endDate /><_entryAuthor><![CDATA[mss32]]></_entryAuthor><_entryCreated>2014-12-03T13:37:25</_entryCreated><_sequence>8</_sequence><_id>03c89ccf-3004-46b4-932d-adf92749b6b7</_id><_parentEntryId /><_shortcutAction /><_responseCount>-1</_responseCount><_responses /><_properties /><_associatedRubrics /><_linkedLessonEntries /></_lessonEntry><_lessonObject><_objectId><![CDATA[58C923421A54482BB9B307A3E0E62329]]></_objectId><_objectType><![CDATA[FOLDER]]></_objectType><_editMask><![CDATA[MRG-141218-143311-MSS32]]></_editMask><_linkMask><![CDATA[*-*-*-*-*-*]]></_linkMask><_title><![CDATA[Course Project]]></_title><_subtitle><![CDATA[Instructions for completing the project is in this folder  ]]></_subtitle><_pageFormat>2</_pageFormat><_linkUrl /><_linkTarget><![CDATA[_self]]></_linkTarget><_objectEditableBy>32</_objectEditableBy><_iconUrl /><_helpUrl /><_objectAuthor><![CDATA[mss32]]></_objectAuthor><_objectCreated>2014-12-03T13:37:25</_objectCreated><_deleted>0</_deleted><_attributes /><_pageText><![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fuel Performance Project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: rgb(255, 255, 0);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(0, 0, 0); font-family: Tahoma, Verdana, Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: auto; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: auto; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(255, 0, 0);&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FINAL REPORT DUE DATE:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;5/05/15 By Midnight ET&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
FRAPCON methodology comparison and parameter study. FRAPCON is a steady-state fuel performance code used to simulate fuel performance for a single-pin geometry. &lt;br /&gt;
There were two lectures that focused on the differences that application methodologies can have on calculated fuel rod thermal mechanical criteria. &lt;br /&gt;
For this project the group will examine what the differences are between best estimate, bounding, and statistical methods. The group is provided with a mostly-complete FRAPCON &lt;br /&gt;
best estimate (nominal conditions) input deck, a FRAPCON input user manual, and an executable version of FRAPCON.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The student will run FRAPCON at the nominal input settings and provide plots of:&lt;br /&gt;
1.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Power history vs time&lt;br /&gt;
2.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Rod internal pressure vs time&lt;br /&gt;
3.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Fuel Centerline temperature vs time&lt;br /&gt;
4.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Fuel Average Temperature vs time&lt;br /&gt;
5.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Pellet-Cladding gap size vs time &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The objective of this project is to understand and quantify the effect that modeling methodologies and uncertainty treatment can have on fuel rod results. &lt;br /&gt;
Once the group understands the best estimate runs and has created the five plots, the uncertainty treatment will be examined. &lt;br /&gt;
The group will apply the bounding methodology and then the statistical best estimate methodology described in the class notes.&lt;br /&gt;
The results should be plotted with the best estimate results and discuss the difference the modeling methods have on the end results. &lt;br /&gt;
The uncertainties to be considered are provided in the following table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;489&quot; height=&quot;124&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;$ENTRY_PATH$Untitled.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To determine the appropriate direction, each uncertainty should be applied individually. A parameter study should first be performed for each parameter with the&lt;br /&gt;
addition/subtraction of its respective uncertainty from the nominal value. The goal of the parameter study is to observe which direction yields the most limiting results &lt;br /&gt;
for rod internal pressure and fuel temperature. It should be noted that sometimes these may be competing effects dependent upon whether the group is trying to &lt;br /&gt;
maximize rod internal pressure or fuel temperature. The groups should plot the effect of varying each parameter on the rod internal pressure and fuel centerline&lt;br /&gt;
temperature for each individual parameter.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Once the direction of each uncertainty is determined, the bounding method should be performed. This involves setting all of the varied parameters at their values&lt;br /&gt;
which produce the maximum deviation from the best-estimate results for the rod internal pressure and fuel centerline temperature. For example, the combination&lt;br /&gt;
of parameters that leads to the minimum fuel centerline temperature should be reported. These values to apply should be known from studying the effects that &lt;br /&gt;
each parameter had on these output parameters. This should be done for both the minimum and maximum deviations from both the rod internal pressure and the fuel centerline temperature.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Then, the statistical method is applied. The statistical method should take the results for each uncertainty parameter set in its most limiting direction and&lt;br /&gt;
subtract the result from the best estimate value. This delta represents the effect that uncertainty has on the pressure or temperature. This is then repeated for each&lt;br /&gt;
uncertainty and then convoluted together via the Root-Mean-Square method. This method was covered during a lecture, and there is extensive literature on the RMS method on the internet.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If the group notes that one combination of parameters and uncertainties yields different results for rod internal pressure and fuel temperature,&lt;br /&gt;
then this activity should be repeated for rod internal pressure and fuel temperature. The results for the statistical method and bounding method are to be compared and discussed. &lt;br /&gt;
Make sure to compare with nominal results as well.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Additionally each group will modify the fuel rod power history based upon the table provided and compare it to the base power history provided. &lt;br /&gt;
The student should discuss the differences between the results and what type of fuel management would lead to the power histories being observed. &lt;br /&gt;
The number of fuel rod power histories to analyze depends on the size of the groups, as will be specified.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
All fuel centerline temperature results should be compared to the UO2 melting temperature,&lt;br /&gt;
and each group should compare the simulated rod internal pressures and the system pressure and provide discussion of the results.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;]]></_pageText><_drmProtected>False</_drmProtected><_isShared>False</_isShared><_dRM /></_lessonObject><_logs /><_access /></Folder>